So the correct answer is this check here.
الجواب الصحيح هو عبارة التحقّق هذه.
While not dice one is the same as dice two and dice two is the same as dice three.
While(!(dice1 == dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2 == dice3)).
Let's try them all one by one and see why only this one works.
لنجرّب كافة الخيارات واحدة تلو واحدة لنعرف لماذا هذه هي العبارة الوحيدة التي ستعمل.
Let's try out this condition here.
لنجرّب هذا الشرط هنا.
while(dice1==dice2 || dice2==dice3).
While(dice1 == dice2 || dice2 == dice3).
Imagine we have this scenario where the three dice are six, three, and one.
تخيّلوا أن لدينا المشهد التالي حيث قيم أحجار النرد الثلاثة هي 6 و3 و1.
Which means dice1 is six,
ما يعني أن dice1 يساوي 6،
dice2 is three, and dice3 is one.
وdice2 يساوي 3، وdice3 يساوي 1.
To see what this entire condition evaluates to,
لنرى نتيجة هذا الشرط بالكامل،
let's take it part by part.
لنتناوله جزءاً جزءاً.
This part here is checking if dice1 is the same as
يتحقق هذا الجزء مما إذا كان dice1 مساوياً لـdice2
dice2 and it's not, so that will be false.
وهما ليسا متساويين، فستكون القيمة هنا هي false.
This part here checks if dice2 is the same as dice3 and it's not,
ويتحقق هذا الجزء مما إذا كان dice2 مساوياً لـdice3، وهما ليسا متساويين،
so that's also false.
فقيمة ذلك هي false أيضاً.
And because those two falses are separated by an or,
ولأن قيمتيّ false هاتين مفصولتين بعلامة or،
it evaluates the entire place to be false,
فإن قيمة هذه العبارة بالكامل تصبح false،
which means we will not step into a while loop and
هذا يعني أننا لن ندخل حلقة while
we will not re-roll even though this scenario should have allowed us to re-roll.
ولن نعيد رمي أحجار النرد على الرغم من أنه كان ينبغي أن تسمح لنا هذه الحالة بذلك.
That means this condition won't work.
هذا يعني أن هذا الشرط لن يعمل.
Okay. Let's try this condition instead,
حسناً، لنجرّب هذا الشرط بدلاً منه.
dice1 is the same as dice2,
dice1 == dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2 == dice3.
If we go with the same scenario again,
إذا مررنا بالحالة نفسها مرة أخرى،
so dice1 is six,
بحيث أن dice1 يساوي 6،
dice2 is three, and dice3 is one.
وdice2 يساوي 3، وdice3 يساوي 1.
This part evaluates to false and this part also evaluates to false.
سيكون ناتج تقييم هذا الجزء false وسيكون ناتج تقييم هذا الجزء false أيضاً.
And those two falses are separated with an and,
وقيمتا false هاتان مفصولتين بعلامة AND،
which means the entire thing is also evaluated to false.
ما يعني أنه سيكون ناتج تقييم العبارة بالكامل هو false.
So it will not re-roll.
فلن تتم إعادة رمي أحجار النرد.
And in this scenario it should have,
وكان ينبغي أن يحدث ذلك في هذه الحالة،
so that also doesn't work.
لذا، لن تعمل هذه العبارة أيضاً.
Okay, let's try, while(dice1!= dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2!= dice3).
حسناً، لنجرّب while(dice1 != dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2 != dice3).
So, let's try this scenario again,
لنرجّب هذه الحالة مرة أخرى،
where dice1 is six,
حيث dice1 يساوي 6،
dice2 is three, and dice3 is one.
وdice2 يساوي 3، وdice3 يساوي 1.
Now, this is checking if dice1 is not the same as dice2,
هذه تتحقق مما إذا كانت dice1 لا يساوي dice2،
and they're not the same so that evaluates to true.
وهما ليسا متساويين، فيكون ناتج التقييم هو true.
This also checks if they're not the same and three and one are not the same,
تتحقق هذه أيضاً ما إذا كانا غير متساويين، و3 لا تساوي 1 بالفعل،
so that evaluates to true as well.
فيكون ناتج تقييم الشرط هنا هو true أيضاً.
And those two trues are separated with an and,
وتفصل علامة AND قيمتي true هاتين،
so this entire thing evaluates to true and allows us to re-roll.
فناتج تقييم هذا الشرط بأكمله هو true وسيسمح لنا بإعادة الرمي.
And in that scenario, we should be re-rolling which is perfect.
ويجدر بنا إعادة الرمي في هذه الحالة، فهذا ممتاز.
But what if the scenario was something like this?
لكن ماذا لو كانت الحالة شبيهة بما يلي؟
Where we had two threes and just one.
حيث لدينا قيمتان مقدارهما 3 وقيمة واحدة مقدارها 1.
In this case, dice1 would be three,
في هذه الحالة، dice1 سيساوي 3،
dice2 would also be three and dice3 would be one.
وdice2 سيساوي 2، وdice3 سيساوي 1.
So if we have a look at this part here,
لذا، إذا نظرنا إلى هذا الجزء هنا،
it evaluates that dice1 and dice2 are not the same although they are,
فسيكون ناتج تقييمه أن dice1 وdice2 ليسا متساويين، بالرغم من أنهما كذلك،
so that evaluates to false.
فستكون قيمة هذا الشرط هي false.
This one checks if they're not the same and they're not the same so that's true.
ويتحقق هذا الجزء مما إذا كانا غير متساويين، وهما ليسا كذلك، وبالتالي تكون قيمته true.
But the false and true are separated by an and,
لكن تفصل إشارة AND بين false وtrue،
which means since one of them is false the whole thing becomes
ما يعني أنه بما أن إحدى القيمتين هي false فبالتالي تصبح قيمة العبارة بأكملها false،
false and it doesn't step into re-roll even though it should have.
وهذا لن يسمح لنا بإعادة الرمي بالرغم من أنه كان من المفترض أن يفعل ذلك.
So that partially works,
هذا الخيار يقوم بالمطلوب جزئياً
but in some situations it will not allow us to re-roll when we should have.
لكنه في بعض الحالات لن يسمح لنا بإعادة الرمي عندما يجدر بنا ذلك.
So that doesn't work either.
لذا، لن ينفع هذا الخيار أيضاً.
Now finally, if we try while(!(dice1 == dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2 == dice3)){.
وأخيراً، إن جرّبنا While(!(dice1 == dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2 == dice3))،
Let's try this scenario again,
لنجرّب هذه الحالة مجدداً.
three three and one.
3 و3 و1.
So dice1 is three,
أي أن dice1 يساوي 3،
dice2 is also three,
وdice2 يساوي 3 أيضاً،
and dice3 is just one.
وdice3 يساوي 1.
This part evaluates to true because both dice are the same.
يكون ناتج تقييم هذا الجزء هو true لأن حجريّ النرد هذين متساويان.
This one evaluates to false because three and one are
ويكون ناتج تقييم هذا الجزء هو false لأن 3 و1 مختلفان عن بعضهما،
different and that is separated with an and,
والجزآن مفصولان بإشارة AND،
so the true and false evaluate to false.
فيكون ناتج تقييم true وfalse هي false.
But this is all surrounded with a not,
لكن هذه العبارة بأكملها محاطة بإشارة NOT،
which means that this force turns into a true.
ما يعني أن قيمة false هذه ستتحوّل إلى true.
And in that scenario the loop would step in and re-roll.
وفي هذه الحالة، سندخل في الحلقة التي ستعيد الرمي.
Now you could go and try all the different scenarios that you could think of.
يمكنكم الآن أن تجربوا جميع الحالات المختلفة التي يمكنك التفكير بها.
And every time it should step inside the while loop it will.
وكلما يتوجب عليها الدخول في حلقة while، ستدخل بالفعل.
Let's have a look at a scenario where all three dice match,
لنلقِ نظرة على حالة تتساوى فيها الأحجار الثلاثة،
which is the condition that the while should not re-roll.
وهي حالة لا يتوجب فيها على حلقة while أن تعيد الرمي.
In this case all dice are equal to three.
في هذه الحالة، جميع أحجار النرد تحمل القيمة 3.
So when we start to evaluate this part evaluates to true because they're both threes.
فعندما نبدأ في إيجاد ناتج التقييم، يكون ناتج تقييم هذا الجزء هو true لأن قيمة كليهما 3.
This one also evaluates to true and two trues
وناتج تقييم هذا أيضاً هو true، وهكذا فإن قيمتيّ true
separated with an and entirely evaluates to true.
تفصل بينهما إشارة AND يكون ناتج تقييمها هو true بالكامل.
And that's also rounded with a not which means that this becomes false.
وذلك كله محاط بإشارة NOT، ما يعني أن هذه القيمة تصبح false.
Now, in this scenario we do not want to step inside
لا نريد دخول الحلقة في هذه الحالةـ
the loop and that's exactly what happens here with this check condition.
وهذا بالضبط ما يحدث هنا مع شرط التحقق هذا.
So this also works.
إذن، إنه يعمل مع هذه الحالة أيضاً.